Guide to the Faith Holsaert Papers, 1950-2011 RL.00566
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Faith Holsaert papers
1950-2011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00566
10.2 Linear Feet 6525 items
Faith Holsaert is a Civil Rights and LGBT community activist. The collection contains correspondence, newsletters, publications, and other materials relating to the activities of Faith Holsaert from the 1960s to the present. A large portion of the collection consists of correspondence and ephemera from her involvement in the Civil Rights movement, including SNCC, and the women's rights movement. Also includes materials from the writing and publishing of Hands on the Freedom Plow, some of which is restricted. The collection also has a large amount of personal memorabilia and materials relating to Holsaert's childhood and family. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Access Restrictions
Box 6 is closed to research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 2008 (2008-0277), 7.5 lin. ft.
Gift, 2010 (2010-0220), 1.2 lin. ft.
Gift, 2011 (2011-0150), 1.5 lin. ft.
Biographical Note
Faith Holsaert is a civil rights and community activist. She was born in New York in 1943, and took a year off from Barnard after her freshman year in 1962 to work with the SNCC. She was one of the earliest female student field workers. She worked on a voter registration project in Albany, Georgia, and on the Mississippi Summer Project. Subsequent to her civil rights work, Holsaert has worked on behalf of the back-to-the-land movement in New Mexico, labor relations in West Virginia, the Brown Berets, the anti-war movement, and LBGT rights. She is a co-editor of the book "Hands on the Freedom Plow: Personal Accounts of Women in SNCC" (2012), and has written elsewhere about her experiences in the civil rights movement. She currently lives in Durham, NC.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, newsletters, publications, and other materials relating to the activities of Faith Holsaert from the 1960s to the present. A large portion of the collection consists of correspondence and ephemera from her involvement in the Civil Rights movement, including SNCC, and the women's rights movement. Also includes materials from the writing and publishing of Hands on the Freedom Plow, some of which is restricted. The collection also has a large amount of personal memorabilia and materials relating to Holsaert's childhood and family.
Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
African Americans -- Civil rights -- Mississippi -- History -- 20th century; African Americans -- Civil rights -- Georgia -- History -- 20th century; Civil rights -- Mississippi -- History -- 20th century; Lesbians -- United States -- History; West Virginia -- Social conditions; Civil rights -- Georgia -- History -- 20th century; African American women civil rights workers -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Women political activists -- United States; Southern States -- Race relations -- History -- 20th century; Civil rights demonstrations -- United States -- History -- 20th century; United States -- Race relations -- History -- 20th century; Albany (Ga.); Social justice -- United States -- History -- 20th century; African Americans -- Social conditions -- Southern States; Newsletters; Albany (Ga.) -- History; CD-ROMs; VHS; Women's rights -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Audiocassettes; Feminism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Pamphlets; Voter registration -- Georgia; Voter registration -- Mississippi; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Holsaert, Faith
- Correspondence
  - Family
    - Daddy/Betty/Shai (Box 2)
    - Memorabilia, 1985-1986 and undated (Box 2)
    - Madre (Box 3)
    - Daddy: appraisals (Box 3)
    - Daddy: legal and administrative II (Box 3)
    - Faith and Hillel (Box 3)
    - Shai (Box 3)
    - Family chronology, 1987 Dec. (Box 3)
    - Froggy album, 1990 Dec. (Box 3)
    - Carmela, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Childhood: Faith and Shai/Deb, 1950s (Box 1)
  - Candy Keely/Carole Gordon/Amina (Box 1)
  - Letters from Writing Friends (Box 1)
  - To my mother (Box 1)
  - From James Holsaert (Box 1)
  - Jan Chapin, 1972-1982 (Box 1-2)
  - Crosing (Faith and Shai's godparents) (Box 1)
  - Hillel, Lickert, Celia (Box 1)
  - From Shai, 1978-1984 (Box 1)
  - Madre, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Eunice Holsaert, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Cora, Patricia, and Pauline Holsaert (Box 1)
  - Charity Bailey (Box 1)
  - Friends, etc., 1960s (Box 1)
  - Friends, 1970s, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Friends, 1980s (Box 1)
  - MFA graduate residency, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - David H., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Don Breeder, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Eve Shelnutt, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Frank Conroy, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1994, 8 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1999, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 2)
- Radical/Leftist literature
  - Kathy Boudin, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Brief of Contestants Urging the Vacating of Seats, U.S. House of Representatives (Box 4)
  - Socialist literature, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Women in prison, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - On the Issues: The Progressive Women's Quarterly, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Two Interviews: Corky Gonzalez and ChaCha Jimenez, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Guy Who Controls Your Future (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Communist Manifesto (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Hard Times in Detroit, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - GE: Profile of a Corporation, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Consumption: Domestic Imperialism (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - PLP: A Critique (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Problems of U.S. Capitalism (Box 5)
  - They Say, All Women Must Be Commandos (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Tierra-O-Muerte (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Race and Class (vol. 35, no. 2-3) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - If an Agent Knocks: Federal Investigation and Your Rights (Box 5)
  - U.S. Capitalism in Crisis, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - To Feel Within the Water (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Repression and Resistance: An Information Manual (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Cracking the Color Line, [undated] (Box 4)
  - Black Panther literature, 1962-1969 (Box 4)
  - Monthly Review: An Independent Socialist Magazine (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - 1978 July-Aug. (Box 5)
    - 1979 Mar. (Box 5)
    - 1979 Apr. (Box 5)
    - 1979 July-Aug. (Box 5)
    - 1979 Dec. (Box 5)
- Research and project documentation
  - MFA bibliographies (Box 1)
  - Katherine Anne Porter paper, undated (Box 1)
  - Guardian (Box 1)
  - Political Prisoners, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Pittston Coal Company, 1987-1989 (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered miscellaneous materials (Box 2)
  - Cash Response (Box 2)
  - Cuban coins (Box 2)
  - Bibliographic annotations, 1986, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Book reviews, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Bibliographic annotations, 1982, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Summer work archive, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Chatfield book (Box 3)
  - Klekota Interview materials, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Klekotka Master's Thesis, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Dear Ms. Klekota, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Interviews with Me Archive (Box 3)
  - Interview with Faith Holsaert by Dr. Jean Smith-Young, May 29, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Self (Box 3)
- Mississippi Summer Project
  - Mississippi Summer Project pamphlet, [1964] (Box 4)
  - A Primer For Delegates to the Democratic National Comvention, [1964] (Box 4)
  - SNCC mobilization letter, [1964] (Box 4)
  - SNCC recruiting letter, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Northern Student Movement Fact Sheet, [1964] (Box 4)
  - Northern Support Program, 1965 (Box 4)
  - SNCC letter, 1965 (Box 4)
  - "The General Condition of the Mississippi Negro", SNCC, 1963 (Box 4)
  - "Preliminary Survey on the Condition of the Negro Farmers ...", 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Mississippi Freedom Schools", SNCC, 1964 (Box 4)
  - "Missisippi Freedom Schools," Staughton Lynd, 1964 (Box 4)
  - "A Chronology of Violence and Intimidation in Mississippi Since 1961," [1964] (Box 4)
  - SNCC Freedom Singers pamphlet, [undated] (Box 4)
  - SNCC Newsletter, May 1967 (Box 4)
  - SNCC Newsletter, June/July 1967 (Box 4)
  - SNCC Newsletter excerpt reprint, June/July, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Challenge of the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, January 14, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, February 3, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, February 18, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, March 3, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, May 5, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, May 19, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, June 30, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, October 28, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Student Voice, November 25, 1964 (Box 4)
  - New York SNCC Office Newsletter, October, 1966 (Box 4)
  - New York SNCC Office Newsletter, November, 1966 (Box 4)
  - New York SNCC Office Newsletter, February 1967 (Box 4)
  - New York SNCC Office Newsletter, April, 1967 (Box 4)
  - New York SNCC Office Newsletter, May, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Fiery Cross (KKK publication), December 15, 1961 (Box 4)
  - The Southern Patriot, June, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Boycott in Crisfield, MD, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Copy of Bob Moses letter from Magnolia Jail, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Revolution in Mississippi, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Mississippi Subversion of the Right to Vote, [undated] (Box 4)
  - SNCC meeting minutes, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Ella Baker 75th birthday celebration, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Racism, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Mississippi Baker Conference, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Misc. SNCC materials, 1978-1996 (Box 4)
  - SNCC, 1988 (Box 4)
    - SNCC, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Fact Sheet on the Arrest of Curtis Hayes Williams, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Dear President Doe, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Points of Inquiry, Pressure, and Support, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Dear Band of Brothers and Sisters, 1988 (Box 4)
    - SNCC Trinity College Conference pamphlet, 1988 (Box 4)
- Southwest Georgia Voter Registration Project
  - Special Report: Albany [Georgia], 1962 (Box 4)
  - Voter Registration Drive, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
  - Southwest Voter Registration Project, 1963 (Box 4)
  - SNCC Survery: Current Field Work, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Eyewitness in Albany, [1963] (Box 4)
  - C.B. King election poster, [1964] (Box 4)
  - "I am the mother of Miss Joe Ann Christian," [1963] (Box 4)
  - Voter registration narrative, [undated] (Box 4)
  - Holsaert's job description, [1963] (Box 4)
  - Notes for a talk on Albany, Georgia, [undated] (Box 4)
  - SNCC letter to Holsaert, 1963 (Box 4)
  - New York Times reprint, 1962 (Box 4)
  - l-r: Penny Patch, Charles Jones(?), Peggy Damond, [1962-1963], 1 photographs (Box 4)
  - Voter's Oath, Georgia, [1962] (Box 4)
  - "Look Big Meeting!" flyer, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Albany Movement Mass Meeting Program, [1962] (Box 4)
  - Letter from Peg, 1962 (Box 4)
  - SNCC action plan, [undated] (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, [ca. 1962-1963] (Box 4a)
  - The New Barbarians, [1962-1963] (Box 4a)
  - "Odds on Freedom: Gambler's Choice in Georgia" Peter de Lissovoy, 1964 (Box 4a)
  - Albany, Georgia Needs Nursery Schools, [1964] (Box 4a)
  - The Southwest Georgia Project for Community Education, 1969 (Box 4a)
  - The Albany South-West Georgia Movement, 1981 (Box 4a)
  - Celebrating the Southwest Georgia Movement, 2000 (Box 4a)
  - Reviewing Our Past to Chart Our Future, 2000 (Box 4a)
  - Harrison thesis, 2001 (Box 4a)
  - C.B. King, 2002 (Box 4a)
  - Albany, Georgia Newsletters (Box 4a)
    - November 3, 1962 (Box 4a)
    - November 7, 1962 (Box 4a)
    - November 9, 1962 (Box 4a)
    - November 12-18, 1962 (Box 4a)
    - November 18, 1962 (Box 4a)
    - December 1, 1962 (Box 4a)
    - January 8, 1963 (Box 4a)
    - January 16, 1963 (Box 4a)
    - January 22, 1963 (Box 4a)
    - January 29, 1963 (Box 4a)
    - February 9, 1963 (Box 4a)
    - March 4, 1963 (Box 4a)
  - Correspondence (Box 4a)
    - Family (Box 4a)
      - Misc. correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 4a)
      - Letter from Holsaert to Barnard Dean, September 19, 1962 (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, [undated] (1) (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, [undated] (2) (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, [undated] (3) (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, [undated], (4) (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, [undated], (5) (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, October 26, [1962] (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, November 9, 1962 (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, December 10, [1962] (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother with Barnard enclosure, December 10, 1962 (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, December 21, [1962] (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother, [1963] (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, January 1, 1963 (Box 4a)
      - Letter from mother, January 23, 1963 (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother, April 15, [1963] (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother, April 21, [1963] (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother, May 25, [1963] (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother and sister, [1962] (1) (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother and sister, [1962] (2) (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother and sister, [1962] (3) (Box 4a)
      - Letter to mother and sister, [1962] (4) (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, [1962] (5) (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, November 2, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, [1963] (1) (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, [1963] (2) (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, January 16, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, March 2, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, March 8, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, March 15, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, April 1, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, May 23, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, May 30, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, June 28, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to mother and sister, July 20, [1963] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from father, January 3, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from father, January 21, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from father, October 18, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from father, October 30, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from father, November 9, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from father, December 9, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from grandmother, December 31, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to sister, [undated] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to sister, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to sister, January 23, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from sister, [undated] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from sister, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from sister, December 2, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Leko, [undated] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Leko, October 28, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Leko, December 31, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter to Leko, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to Leko, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter to Leko, April 16, [1963] (Box 4b)
    - Christian Family (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dessie Christian, October 20, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dessie Christian, January 3, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dessie Christian, April 27, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dessie Christian, August 8, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dessie Christian, October 5, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dessie Christian, January 30, 1968 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dessie Christian, December 22, 1969 (Box 4b)
      - Letter to Wendy from Dessie Christian, March 4, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, [1964] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, July 12, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, August 9, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, September 29, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, October 3, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, October 5, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, December 1, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian, February 28, 1965 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian Mants, January 31, 1968 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian Mants, April 7, 1968 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian Mants, January 15, 1970 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joann Christian Mants, February 20, 1986 (Box 4b)
    - Friends (Box 4b)
      - Letter from DH, [undated] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Ralph, [undated] (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Joy, January 24, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Peg, September 27, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Bob, October 15, 1962 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from high school history teacher, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Betsy, January 3, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Rochelle Haimer, January 7, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Frankie, January 15, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Anne Braden, January 15, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from her high school history teacher, January 19, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Dorie, January 19, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Johnnie Ruth, January 24th, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from John, September 21, 1963 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Margaret King, February 21, 1964 (Box 4b)
      - Letter from Wendy, December 8, [1964] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to Betsy and Paul, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to Howard and Clarice, [1962] (Box 4b)
      - Letter to Howard and Clarice, January 11, [1963] (Box 4b)
- West Virginia
  - Appalachian peridicals, 1971-1976 (Box 1)
  - Recht Dee, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Pauley case, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Rainbow (WV and SREP), 1991 (Box 1)
  - Lesbian community newsletter. 1990 (Box 1)
  - Women's Health Center, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - WV Rainbow Univ. Healthcare, 1990 (Box 1)
  - West Virginia Environmental Activism, 1992
  - Coal Employees project, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Conspiracy in Coal booklet (Box 4)
- Southern Social Justice Work
  - Anti-KKK (Box 2)
  - Hamlet, NC, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Gulf Coast Tenants, 1991-1991 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Furniture Workers 282 (Box 1)
  - SCEF Society (Box 4)
  - Asbestosis (Box 4)
  - Anne Braden (Box 4)
  - Rainbow SREP (Box 4)
  - Black elected officials (Box 4)
  - Center for Democratic Renewal (Box 4)
  - Christie Institution (Box 4)
  - Cold War (Box 4)
  - KKK (Box 4)
  - Lexington women's prison (Box 4)
  - Movement support network (Box 4)
  - NCARRV (Box 4)
  - Poultry workers (Box 4)
  - SOS Article (Box 4)
  - Robeson Co., N.C. (Box 4)
  - Up and Out of Poverty (Box 4)
  - SE Project (Box 4)
  - So Fight Back (Box 4)
  - SOC Environmental Justice (Box 4)
  - SOC (Box 4)
  - SOC Youth (Box 4)
  - SOC Labor (Box 4)
  - SOC, 1996 (Box 4)
  - SOC Newletter (Box 4)
  - SOC Board (Box 4)
  - Freedomways, 1964 (Box 4)
  - KKK: A History of Racism and Violence (Box 4)
  - Freedom is a Constant Struggle program (Box 4)
  - AmeriKKKa, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Frederick Douglass (Box 4)
  - Life and Times of Frantz Fanon (Box 4)
  - Project South (Box 2)
  - Southern Organizing Committee for Economics and Social Justice, 2001 (Box 2)
- Hands on the Freedom Plow materials
  Access Restrictions
  Box 6 is closed to research.
  - Editors' Correspondence, 2000-2007 (Box 6)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    RESTRICTED.
  - Correspondence, 1995-2002 (Box 6)
  - Book press, 2010 and undated (Box 6)
  - Book proof, 2010 (Box 6)
  - University of Illinois Press memorandums and book editors, 2005-2007 (Box 6)
  - University of Illinois Press marketing for book, 2010 (Box 6)
  - Drafts and revisions, 2009 and undated (Box 6)
  - Revisions for bridges, 2008 (Box 6)
  - First review and annotations, 2007-2008 (Box 6)
  - CDs of text (removed to Duke's electronic records server) (Box 6)
  - Book structure, 2000-2006 (Box 6)
  - Address list for manuscripts and edit team assignments, 1997-2006 (Box 6)
  - Contract/business, 2007 (Box 6)
  - Introductions and bridges for final introduction, 2005-2007 and undated (Box 6)
  - Background research articles, 1996-1997 and undated (Box 6)
  - Business and finances, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Meeting minutes and progress reports, 2006-2007 (Box 6)
  - Letters to contributors, 1996-2007 (Box 7)
  - Brown, Marie: Correspondence and comments, 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Baker, Ella: "The Black Woman in the Civil Rights Struggle: A Long View," 1969 (Box 7)
  - Sarah Lawrence Conference, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Interviews and SGWA texts, 1962 and undated (Box 7)
  - Presses other than University of Illinois, 2000-2004 (Box 7)
  - Drafts, 2000, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Drafts and editorial notes, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Manuscript sections 1 and 2, 2002 July (Box 9)
  - Drafts and editing, 2002 July, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Drafts, 2003 Sept. (Box 9)
  - Binder/drafts, 2006, folder 1 of 4 (Box 9)
  - Binder/drafts, 2006, folders 2 to 4 (Box 10)
  - Publicity, 2 pamphlets (Box 10)
  - Poster (Oversize-box 51)
  - Hands on the Freedom Plow poster (Oversize-folder 1)
- Audiovisual Materials
  - Faith Holsaert interview, April 2, 2006, 1 cdrs (Box 10)
  - Joanne C.M., July 9, 1997, 2 audiocassettes (Box 10)
  - Jamie C.R., July 6, 1997, 1 audiocassettes (Box 10)
  - Ratha, July 7, 1997, 1 audiocassettes (Box 10)
  - Carolyn D., undated, 1 audiocassettes (Box 10)
  - McCree, July, 1997, 1 audiocassettes (Box 10)
  - Black Power: Music of a Revolution, 1 cdrs (Box 5)
- Women's Rights
  - Off Our Backs: A Women's News Journal, 1980 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Women: A Journal of Liberation, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Feminist Art Journal, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Aphra (vol. 5, no. 1), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Quest: Feminist Quarterly, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Woman News, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chrysalis: A Magazine of Women's Culture (No. 10) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Up from Under (vol. 1, no. 4) (Box 5)
  - Up from Under (vol. 1, no. 3), 1971 Jan., 2 copies (Box 5)
  - Women's Health pamphlets, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Women's meetings, West Virginia, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lesbian feminist literature, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Socialist feminist literature, 1970s (Box 5)
  - Women and labor (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Second Wave (vol. 3, no. 1) (Box 5)
  - Yale Law Journal: Equal Rights Amendment, 1971 Apr. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Ramparts, 1974 Sept. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Our Bodies, Our Selves, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Women's Free Express, 1974 Mar.-Sept., 3 pamphlets (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Southern Voices (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Motive: Lesbian/Feminist issue, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Second Wave (vol. 2, no. 4) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Up from Under, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Women and coal, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Appalachian women's movement, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Sterilization abuse, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Quaranties and Death, Mab Segrest, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Lesbian battery, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Feminist Revolution: Redstockings, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Socialist Feminism: A Strategy for the Women's Movement, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)